BU Records: University Committee on AIDS, Inclusive: 1980-1989, undated, Bulk: 1987-1988
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: University Committee on AIDS
Inclusive: 1980-1989, undated, Bulk: 1987-1988
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/267
Baylor University Committee on AIDS
8 document boxes.
The BU Records: University Committee on AIDS consists of documents produced by the committee, such as informational brochures, surveys, and drafts of AIDS policy statements, as well as research materials collected by committee members.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Originals/Duplicates
Mix of some originals and some copies.
Biography/Profile
The Baylor University Committee on AIDS was formed on 1988 April 21 under the leadership of Dr. William Hillis, though it had operated for about seven months prior to the name change as Baylor's Task Force on AIDS. Both the committee and the task force were led by Dr. Hillis, Baylor’s executive vice president for administrative affairs. Created in summer 1987 and having its first meeting 1987 September 22, the Task Force was comprised of ten faculty, staff, and community leaders appointed by Dr. Hillis. Dan McGee, Baylor religion professor, chaired the Task Force, and was succeeded by Sheila Hyde, dean of student life activities. On 1988 March 18, the Board of Trustees approved a seven-point “Baylor University Statement on AIDS” which was composed by the Task Force. The last point of the statement recommended the formation of a “standing committee” to continue the task of researching, developing, and implementing the University’s response to the growing AIDS crisis.
The work of the Committee on AIDS was primarily educational. Chaired by Baylor University law professor Michael Morrison and comprised of over a dozen faculty, staff, and students, the Committee was also involved in advising Baylor on its policies regarding legal and health issues of potential AIDS-infected students and employees. Committee members also collected the most recent literature on the topic and attended various conferences on AIDS. On 1988 November 18, the Committee brought Dr. Richard Keeling, leading authority on HIV/AIDS and professor of medicine at the University of Virginia at Charlottesville, to the Baylor campus to speak at an open forum on AIDS. It is unknown whether the committee still exists or if its function has been absorbed into a broader Health committee's responsibilities.
Scope and Content
The BU Records: University Committee on AIDS covers the years 1980-1989. A small series of committee documents consists of surveys, policy statements, reports, and some correspondence produced by the committee or its members. The bulk of the collection is found in a second series of research materials collected by committee members through attendance at AIDS conferences and independent research. This series contains some correspondence of Michael Morrison, chair of the committee.
Arrangement
The BU Records: University Committee on AIDS was inventoried, but not organized, prior to this finding aid. Most of the existing folder titles, and much of the prior arrangement was kept. Currently the BU Records: University Committee on AIDS is organized into two series: I. Committee Documents, and II. Research Materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/267. Acquired 1989-07-26
Related Resources
Items in related collections
BU Records: Vice President for Student Affairs (William D. Hillis), 1989-1998
Related references
Beller, Richie. "Trustees Release AIDS Policy." Lariat. 1988 March 22, p. 1.
"Editorial: Student Voice Necessary for Proper Perspective." Lariat. 1988 March 23, p. 2.
Gilcrease, Shannon. "Baylor Provides AIDS Testing, Education." Lariat. 1988 October 14, p. 1.
Norville, Scott V. "BU Program to Deal with Issue of AIDS." Lariat. 1988 November 17, p. 1.
Simpson, Chrisanna. "Task Force to Help with AIDS Conference." Lariat. 1988 February 17, p. 4.
Wilkins, Deborah. "New Task Force Prepares to Battle AIDS at Baylor." Lariat. 1987 September 24, p. 1.
Willman, Tina. "Administration Outlines Baylor AIDS Policy." Lariat. 1989 February 17, p. 1.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- History -- 20th century.
Subjects
AIDS (Disease) -- Baylor University.
Genres
Pamphlets.; Reports.
- Committee Documents, 1988-1989, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  The Committee Documents series contains productions of the committee and its members. It includes drafts of the Baylor AIDS policy, a proposed student survey, list of committee members, and some correspondence of committee members.
  - AIDS Survey Proposal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baylor Report: AIDS and the Law, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AIDS Committee Reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AIDS Committee Reports, 1988-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Research Materials, 1980-1989, undated; 2
  The Research Materials series contains items collected by committee members--chiefly Michael Morrison of the Baylor Law School--in the course of its work to provide guidance and education to Baylor University on the AIDS issue. The series includes such items as academic papers, Planned Parenthood pamphlets, copies of state and federal legislation, popular magazine articles, and resource catalogues. Some notes, correspondence and memoranda of committee members is also retained in this series.
  - American College Health Association Resources (1 of 2), 1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American College Health Association Resources (2 of 2), 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Council on Education, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Austin City Ordinance, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Austin AIDS Conference (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Austin AIDS Conference (2 of 2 ), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - AIDS Bills, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Blood Banks Laws, 1987-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - AIDS and Civil Liberties, 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Compulsory Measures, 1984, 1986, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Insurance and AIDS Testing, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ethics, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - AIDS: Guide for Survival, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - AIDS and Hospitals (1of 2), 1987-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - AIDS and Hospitals (2 of 2), 1987-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - AIDS Reporting and Testing (1 of 2), 1987-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - AIDS Reporting and Testing (2 of 2), 1987-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AIDS and other Contagious Diseases (1 of 6), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - AIDS and other Contagious Diseases (2 of 6), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - AIDS and other Contagious Diseases (3 of 6), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - AIDS and other Contagious Diseases (4 of 6), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - AIDS and other Contagious Diseases (5 of 6), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - AIDS and other Contagious Diseases (6 of 6), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Housing, Insurance, Custody, Prisons, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ramifications of the AIDS Crisis for Local Governments, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Senator Helms, Legislation, 1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Medical Views, Discoveries, 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - LAMBDA Newsletters, Science Focus, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1986, 1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - AIDS Policy and Law Newsletter, March-May 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - AIDS Policy and Law Newsletter, June-October 1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - AIDS Policy and Law Newsletter, November-December 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - AIDS Policy and Law Newsletter, January-March 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - AIDS and College Campus, 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Educational Resources (1 of 3), 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Educational Resources (2 of 3), 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Educational Resources (3 of 3), 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Surgeon General Report, 1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - AIDS Testing Program, 1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The AIDS Victim, Legal Issues, 1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - AIDS and the Workplace (1 of 5), 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - AIDS and the Workplace (2 of 5), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - AIDS and the Workplace (3 of 5), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - AIDS and the Workplace (4 of 5), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - AIDS and the Workplace (5 of 5), 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - AIDS, Minorities, and the Law, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Politics of AIDS, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - AIDS and the Law, Sexuality and the Law, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - AIDS: Basic Documents, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board, 1985-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - American College Health Association (1 of 4), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - American College Health Association Board (2 of 4), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - American College Health Association Board (3 of 4), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - American College Health Association Board (4 of 4), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (1 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (2 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (3 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (4 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (5 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (6 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - AIDS and the Workplace, Dallas Task Force (7 of 7), 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - AIDS: Facing Facts, Confronting Fears, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - AIDS: Review of Science, Health Policy, and Law (1 of 2), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - AIDS: Review of Science, Health Policy, and Law (2 of 2), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets on Sexual Abuse, Assault, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: Planned Parenthood (1 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: Planned Parenthood (2 of 2), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets: Waco Crisis Pregnancy Center, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - AIDS and Education, 1986-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - AIDS Information Resources Directory, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Statement of Preliminary Findings, Legislative Task Force on AIDS, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - McLennan Community College Conference, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets (1 of 4), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets (2 of 4), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets (3 of 4), undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets (4 of 4), undated (Box 8, Folder 7)